I just put GPT6 Astra headto-head
against Fable 5.1 across 15 different
use cases that actually apply to my
day-to-day. I'm talking things like web
design, personal organization, taxes,
browser use, vision, and building actual
automations and software. For every
single one of these use cases, I break
down which model did better, how long it
took, and what it cost. So, if you've
been wondering what model to use for
which use case, then this is the video
for you. I don't want to waste any time.
Let's just get straight into it today.
All right, so these are the 15 different
use cases that we have. And like I said,
I chose these because these are things
that I actually see myself doing with
these models. So, there are timestamps
down below if you want to jump around.
And at the very end, I'm going to show
the final sort of like takeaways and
final cost and time breakdown. And by
the way, guys, I've eaten through like
three Codex subscriptions, four cloud
subscriptions, and thousands of dollars
in usage credits. So, I really hope that
this one's helpful. All right, so for
number one, I'm not going to read off
every single prompt, but here's
basically what I asked. I wanted a
McKenzie level presentation on the state
of SMB report for my Hercules Consulting
brand. So, I needed this to be branded
and I needed it to apply to our target
audience with this fake consulting
business. So, that was Claude. You can
see that I gave Codex the exact same
prompt. Now, immediately what I've
noticed is that Codex asks more
questions or GBT6 Astra specifically
asks more questions. You can see right
here, it already asked me questions,
whereas Fable just took this and pretty
much just ran. And that is something I
noticed overall. So, I just wanted to
call that out to start. So, let's take a
look at these two decks. Here is deck
number one. I won't tell you which model
it was yet, but right away I love the
way it feels. It is, you know,
capitalized. It has the branding. This
feels pretty professional so far. Now, I
already did check both of these for the
sources and the verification and they
are good from like the fact perspective,
right? The research they both did was
good. Now, I'm looking more so at the
way they actually formatted this
deliverable. I think we're at a place
now where GBT6 Astra and Fable 5.1,
they're both so so intelligent. You
don't have to worry as much about
fanning out agents and doing research.
It's more to me now about how do they
come back and present this in a way that
tells a story and in something that I
can actually like present over, right?
because that's what we want is we want
to turn that messy data into something
that's readable and something that's
high quality. And right now what I'm
feeling is that this is very very
branded. It matches our color scheme. We
have a footer down here which I love.
It's consistent. We have like structure.
There's columns. Like it did a good job
creating this. The thing that I think
right now though is it's very very
wordy. As far as being able to present
over something like this, it would be
tough because there's so many words and
it's tough to control like where
people's eyes will be looking and what
they'll be speaking about. So, as far as
a presentation deck, not the best, but
as far as like a deliverable you might
turn in, you might send to someone and
not present, this is very good. And
there's a lot of sources down here. This
came out to 35 slides. Now, let's look
at the other version, which right away I
don't like how this isn't capitalized. I
don't know. I just feel like that feels
very professional. We have some images
here, and we have the color scheme as
well. But let's flick through. We
immediately notice that this one is not
as wordy. I immediately feel like this
one's less professional, though, because
of the structure. The other one had like
I don't know, you could tell in each
slide there was like columns. there was
a little bit of like a I don't know
there was a structure to it whereas this
one feels a little bit more abstract. It
feels like one big element. You've got
one big you know title thing and I think
that this one would be a much better
deliverable if I was going to present in
you know in a room full of people. But
overall as we flick through this one
just feels less professional. The vibe I
get is less McKenzie and it's more
Google Slides or like Canva. I don't
know. There's also not like a consistent
footer or our logo isn't on every slide.
So, you know, this sort of fly, it just
doesn't feel very structured and as
professional. Even the sources section
is way smaller, although that does link
the actual sources. So, anyways, this
one was GBT6 Astra and this one was
Fable 5.1. And I will say in this
specific example, I liked Fable better.
So, what I'm going to do here is I'm
going to give Fable the win. So, I'm
just going to put this down here so we
know Fable won this experiment as far as
just the output. But, let's look at the
time and cost. Fable was 37 minutes and
Astra was 23 minutes and Fable was 26
bucks and Astra was 12 bucks. So Astra
was a little less than half the cost as
well as you know 14 minutes faster. So
the question would be if you used Astra
and spent another you know 14 bucks
using Astra to improve V1 would you get
somewhere that you feel better about
than this first version of Fable? So
anyways, right now we'll look at the
time and cost at the very end, but as
far as the deliverable, I liked Fable's
output better here. All right, moving on
to experiment number two. We did a sales
letter. So basically, I said based on
what you know about our certification
program, I didn't give it information. I
told it to, you know, use my AIOS, use
my second brain, use any research to put
together a sales landing page. So
writing the copy that's optimized to
convert. So think about our avatar,
think about their pain, think about all
this. And I don't want it to sound AI
generated. So I'm not going to read the
entire sales letters. That would be
super boring. Just going to do a quick
skim through and talk about which one I
actually thought was better and why. So,
here it was. The one that Fable 5.1
wrote out, you can see it is pretty
long. This one was longer. It was about
2,800 words. And if we go over to GBT's
version, if I come down here, it just
output it right in the chat to me. This
was the one that Astra wrote up. And
this one was more like 1,700 words. So,
it was definitely shorter. Now, quick
disclaimer here. I am not an expert
copywriter. I would want, you know, like
John or someone on my team who is really
good at writing copy to tell me which
one they thought is better. I will say
so far what I've been hearing from my
team is that they are liking the GBT
models lately better for writing whereas
in the past Claude always dominated when
it came to writing. But I will say if I
was a prospective, you know,
certification student and I was reading
these, I honestly here would have picked
Fable. And the reason is because this is
not a cheap program and Fable had things
like questions people ask. Will this get
me hired? Does everyone who joins get
certified? Am I technical enough? I
already run an agency. What if I miss
live classes? The way it formatted this
makes me feel a little bit more
confident or makes me feel more aware of
what I'm getting myself into. It also
had a section about tuition. It also had
a section about who's teaching, who it's
for, who it's not for, how this actual
program works. Whereas the sales letter
over here with Astra just felt a little
bit more, I don't know, it just felt a
little bit more high level. And I think
with the sales letter, it's supposed to
be detailed enough to answer all the
questions and pain that someone's
thinking about when they're considering
paying for a program. So, I will say in
this specific example, I do think that I
liked Fable 5.1's copy more. So, here is
actually what this looked like. Fable
was about four minutes. Astra was about
3 minutes. Fable wrote, okay, I was
wrong about Astra. It wasn't 1,700. It
was actually more like 1300. So, about
half of the words that Fable wrote, but
Astra came in at $143 whereas Fable came
in at almost four bucks. So, here I will
have to say again that I think that
Fable won this challenge as far as just
like a oneshot prompt and the initial
output. All right, so moving on to use
case number three. Now, unfortunately,
guys, I'm going to have pretty much
everything blurred out here because this
is about my taxes, right? And this is
one of those things where you want
something that is very smart to be able
to do this and in a way that you trust.
So, I'm just going to go through high
level the way I feel when I look at
these outputs. This first one was Fable
5.1. And before I get into it, I do want
to say in this example, GBT Astra asked
me like seven questions before it
started, whereas Fable didn't. So that
alone makes me feel more confident in
Astra's output. But let's look through
here. We go through basically from
January of this year to June of this
year. So Q1 and Q2 of this year. It
pulls all of the numbers. It looks at
federal and state. It looks at things
that I need to read. It goes to the
input and it shows me all of these
different things as far as the
parameters, the notes, the values, the
sources. And Fable gave me like a
decision logic. It said, "Hey, if you
fit into this bucket, do this. If you
fit into this bucket, do this." Whereas
Astra just asked me those questions and
then gave me that recommendation.
Anyways, we have a um P&L. We have some
projections. So, for the rest of the
year, what I might be estimating to pay.
We have tax calculations here for the
individual return and all of the
entities that are passed through. We've
got payments. We've got things that are
flagged. And then we have the actual
sources it pulled from. So, it's not
bad. It's a really good deliverable like
light years ahead of what used to
happen. But now we have the one from
Astra. We have the actual information as
far as start here. This is what it did.
We have monthly results. We have the tax
forecast. We have, okay, that looks very
good. We have all these payments. We
have inputs and open items. So, these
are other things that I might need to
answer, but this is just way more
tailored. It's easier to read as well.
We have the source checks. We have the
transaction ledger. And this one is
basically every single transaction here.
So, this Oh my gosh, this is probably
thousands and thousands of rows. This is
3739 rows of transactions here. And then
we've got all the sources that it pulled
from. Okay, cool. So, overall, this one
I think that Astro won like no question.
It was more tailored. to ask questions.
I think with taxes alone, it gave me
that that feeling of confidence and the
structure of the deliverable was just
better to me. Now, Astra did cost more
here and it took longer to run. So, 40
minutes compared to 22 minutes and 22
bucks compared to 13 bucks. So, even
though it's more expensive, we're kind
of putting that aside right now. As far
as the deliverable, I liked Astra here
more. So, right now we're sitting at
Astra 1 Fable 2. All right. So, this
next one's interesting. I asked it to go
through two of my email accounts and
just look through, you know, potentially
years of emails to help me find
information about subscriptions that I'm
paying for, how much total I've paid
them, you know, um if prices have
increased and things that I need to
cancel, things like that. So, let me
pull up the two outputs. All right, so
here is output number one from Fable
5.1. Now, as we get into the next tabs
on the sheet, I'm sorry, guys, but I am
going to have to blur some of this stuff
out. It's it's financial information.
So, anyways, we have the rundown right
here of the audit. We have the different
emails it looked at. We have the
different types of services,
memberships, programs, retainers,
contractors, insurance, all this type of
stuff. It's looking at the top 10. It's
looking at our different categories, and
it's showing us how to read this sheet.
So, we have all of our active
subscriptions. It's showing me what
email they're associated with. It's
telling me which day of the month I'm
getting build on. It's showing the
current price. It's showing the monthly
equivalent. It's showing me all of the
stats across all the different payments
that we've been making on some sort of
recurring basis. It's flagging things
and it's ranking them as far as
priority. We can see um the different
actual flag notes. So, some of these it
might be unpaid. This one's getting a
price jump. This one's having a seat
creep. This one's having I have two
subscriptions at once. So, maybe we need
to figure out why do I have two
different subscriptions on both emails
there. So, the point being it's able to
look through so much information and
give you all of these things that are
high priority and you can flag them, you
can check them off, you can, you know,
delegate that out to your team. We have
all charges, which actually this sheet
came back completely empty. I'm not sure
why, but this sheet is completely empty.
And then we have contractors and big
payments. So, these are things it looks
like. Anything above
um either a few thousand or if it was a
contractor that was like a onetime
invoice, then it flagged it here as
well. And now, let's go over to the
Astra 6 version. You can see that they
consistently just format Google Sheets a
little bit different. Like, you can kind
of tell Astra likes to make the cells
larger and and wider and taller, whereas
Fable usually keeps them the same. And,
you know, they still do a good job
formatting, but either way, same sort of
thing. At the audit up front, we have
the current recurring baseline of
subscriptions. We have the annualized
baseline tool payments, tool invoices
without confirmation, clawed usage,
other bills, um price changes. It's
flagging everything right here. Priority
review right here. You know, there's a
discount ending, there is contract tier
or contact tier, there is a price
increase, there's a term change, there's
seats and tool overlap. So, it's
flagging all that right away. We then
have all the subscriptions. So, this
shows me a list of every single one. It
gives me the price. It gives me the um
last known bill. Now, this isn't showing
me what date. Oh, there it is. Yeah,
it's showing me every single day of the
month that we have the next one. We have
other bills as well. So, these are kind
of the bigger like bigger contracts um
contractors or or bigger bills. We have
payments. So, this is also like every
single one. And I think this is what
Fable was trying to do on this tab with
all charges, but for some reason just
didn't come through. So, we have this
here. And then we have also other notes
as far as different topics and different
things to sort of be aware of. So, this
is kind of like what it was flagging.
So, overall here, I will say that Astra
gave me a better output. It just, you
know, Fable messed up one sheet
completely and Astro was cheaper here.
So 12 bucks, 12 and a half bucks
compared to about $50, which is insane.
$50 for that output from Fable. Crazy.
It did take 17 minutes whereas Astro
took 30 minutes. But anyways, right now
we are sitting at 2 to2 Astro and Fable.
All right, moving on to number five. We
have meeting analysis. So I asked it to
look through all of my leadership
meetings and my syncs with John and
looking at other meetings that are
relevant to the team. And I wanted it to
understand or I wanted it to tell me
what are the biggest pain points, three
biggest pain points and one of the
highest value automations that we could
build to remove some constraints and
help us scale faster. So Fable gave me
the biggest pain points of me being the
single production and review engine
which is something that I've talked
about 25 of 58 meetings. Certification
delivery does not scale past one cohort.
So we're trying to figure out what that
would look like. The critical constraint
of the business is also a large cost
center. 52 students blah blah blah. And
then we also have demand collapsed and
every fix is blocked by unknown work and
untrusted data. Weekly leads fell blah
blah blah. And yeah, all this makes
sense as far as our three biggest pain
points. And then the one automation it
came up with was an AI customer success
layer for theert. One live record per
student built from circle activity
mastery check outputs and attendance.
Students upload case readouts to an
endpoint instead of DMing pat weekly due
dates and reminders so non-submitters go
out through Gmail or behive. I think
this is something that I've wanted to do
and that we've talked about a lot and
that makes a lot of sense based on all
these conversations. And and I also
wanted to note here that Fable 5.1
analyzed 58 meetings and if we go over
to Astra, Astra analyzed 79 meetings. So
it did get the context of 21 more
meetings in here. But anyways, let's
take a look. The first one was that
growth depends too heavily on a few
acquisition channels. Yep, same pain
point I think as Fable pointed out. The
second one is that the customer journey
requires too much personal intervention.
This appeared in undefined AIS plus
onboarding call reser during
certification and leadership still has
to reconstruct status and clarify who
owns what. Okay, interesting. So these
are different pain points than Fable 5.1
found. Now as far as the automation I
would prioritize it came up with the
same thing. A customer success workflow
which would check each student's
onboarding status, unanswered questions,
available progress, identify missteps,
prepare follow-up, all makes sense. Now
in this case I think Astra won again
like before I even thought about the
cost which is absolutely absurd. Astra
still won because I liked its
recommendation about the leadership
stuff and ownership. And I think that's
something that you really want to make
sure you have figured out within a team.
But anyways, if you look here, Astra was
5 12 bucks and Fable 5.1 here was 46
bucks, which just makes no sense to me.
I I'm very very confused on how it costs
that much. I had it look at the session
longs. I also did a slash usage and this
one cost 46 bucks even though the active
agent time was just 6 minutes. So I'm
very confused on where those tokens
went. Like I don't understand why. It
also analyzed less meetings in Astra.
But anyways, that's pretty interesting.
This winner is definitely Astra. So now
we are sitting at 3 to2 Astra to Fable.
All right, so moving on to number six.
This one's super interesting to me. I
gave it this folder, which has over 150
gigabytes of resources and recordings
from our AIS live event in July, and I
asked them to make us basically a a
recap, like an energetic reel, 60
seconds that shows like a recap of the
event that we can use to promote the
next ones and things like that. Now, I'm
really impressed with both of these
outputs. Let me just say because with
how much information it had to look
through and how it had to create a story
and figure out how to put everything
together with music, I think they both
did really really well. So, here is
Fable 5.1.
>> Hello. Hello, AIS Live. My
>> Let's Let's get some energy going in
here.
>> Oh my god, I'm so excited for this. You
guys are throwing out a fantastic event.
>> Literally like logged off yesterday just
buzzing. I had goosebumps. Let's Let's
get you guys paid.
This was an experience that didn't feel
like a webinar.
[music]
It's been a great two days.
Okay, so that was Fable 5.1. Let's take
a look at Astra's version. This has been
so energizing.
[music]
Yesterday I did a workshop where I went
all in on every little tool that I use.
[music]
Cloud code is my primary driver and then
I built like my entire second
brain/personal agent on top of it.
[music]
>> I could go to bed, come back and it'll
still be working, you know, 10 hours
later to try to achieve that goal.
>> [music]
>> It's great to be here. You guys have
done a a fantastic event. Everything's
been super smooth.
You guys have been such an amazing
audience today.
Now, this one, like I said, is really
tough. I think that they both did
different things well. I think that
Asher did a better job of putting like
live clips in there. I think that Fable
did a better job of kind of like gearing
it up for the next event in October.
There were a few moments where there
were some things that were off. Like
Fable had a few moments where the the
timing and the voices were felt like not
very synced. Astra had one weird moment
where it was showing an a video of Russ,
but it said Devon Karns and it was just
like that was clearly off. But I am
going to give the slight edge here to
Astra. But I will say I'm very very
impressed by both of those outputs. I
thought it was given the vague goal,
they both did a really good job of
exploring and creating a story. But
anyways, this one is going to go to
Astra because you can see this stuff
here. Astra took 30 minutes whereas
Fable took 50 and Astra cost 16 bucks
and Fable cost 26 bucks here. Now, next
we did sizzle reels. I basically gave it
an example of a scissor reel that I
really liked or sort of like a sass I
don't know a motion graphic a motion
design video that I liked and I told it
to analyze what was good about it and I
told it to use that as inspiration and
create us one for AIS. So let me show
you guys these outputs. First one is
Fable 5.1
Heat. Heat.
[music]
Okay, now let me play you Astra's
output.
[music]
>> [music]
>> Okay, so Astro wins this one. I mean, I
will say that music is a little bit
annoying that, but besides that, it took
screenshots from AIS. Like, it went in
here and it grabs pictures of the actual
courses. Where was the other one? It
took a picture here, which I thought was
just like I love that idea that it's
thinking, okay, why don't I actually go
get real proof and screenshots from the
thing I'm actually building a reel about
and put it in there. I also love this
like these 3D designs. I don't know, it
just felt like it had depth. You can see
the shadows here as it kind of, you
know, zooms in. I thought that this as
far as the energy that it had was much
better and much higher energy than the
first one from Fable 5.1. Now, let's
take a look at the cost and time. This
one was about similar time, but Fable
5.1 was, you know, a little over half.
So 16 bucks compared to 26 bucks. But
once again, I still think that in this
case, I'm going to take that output from
Astra as the winner. So moving on to
number eight. This one's a little more
out there as far as I probably wouldn't
really be doing this every day for work,
but I had them build me these games. So
we have two different games where you're
a pistachio and you're trying to escape
the kitchen. So I'm just going to go
through these real quick and you're
going to tell me which one you thought
was, you know, sort of like which model.
So, you can see here it's it's uh it's
pretty smooth. I can double jump. I'm
collecting these like cereal bits and I
have to hit these checkpoints to get to
different spots in order to get out of
the kitchen. The physics are real. Like,
I'm bumping into these things and I can
like, you know, hit the spoon and
everything like that. It's pretty easy,
but you know, I I I missed a cereal, but
I'm able to escape and win the game in
about 43 seconds. Okay, now here is the
other version. This one This one
definitely looks a little bit more I
don't know. It looks a little bit more
premium, doesn't it? Um, this obviously
this wall isn't there, but it's just
because we want to be able to see like
this. But this one feels a bit more
premium, I'd say. It also feels smoother
when I'm actually like controlling this.
It is guiding me very specifically,
though. I don't know. I can double jump,
I think. Oh, no. I can't double jump.
The physics seem to be real still. I can
bump into stuff. I can move things. I
can fall into there. Um, we've got hot
stove. Oops. It's interesting though.
They both decided to have like the same
flow as far as you jump up on the drawer
and then you, you know, you jump up on
books to start. You're now on the stove.
You're going over to the sink. I mean,
that's how most kitchens are, but still
the the actual flow is pretty similar.
And now we escaped in this one in 46
seconds. So, similar amount of time. I
did get all of the crumbs in this one.
They were designed very similarly, but I
will say I think that as far as like
feeling realistic and, you know,
physics, I liked this version better and
this version was Astra. Anyways, look at
these stats. They were very, very
similar. So Astra was eight bucks
cheaper, nine bucks cheaper, and it also
took about 40 bucks longer. So very
similar stats. Nothing blew anything out
of the water here, but I would say that
I'm giving this one to Astra. Once
again, that one's subjective. Maybe some
of you guys liked Fable 5.1 more. But
what I think is really important is that
you're applying your own taste and
you're finding your own use cases
because some of these use cases, you
guys might be like, "Well, I actually
liked Fable 5.1 here." Cool. Then you
just figured out maybe you use Fable 5.1
for that use case even though some other
people might use Astra for that use
case. It's all about your own use cases
and your own experiments. Okay, so
moving on to number nine, we have an
actual SAS, like kind of a mini SAS, and
it's an evaluation app. So you should be
able to put in like automations and then
run them against some golden data set
and see the score and understand like
what you need to fix, and then you can
rerun them, and you can generate reports
and things like that. So you can see
here, this is the first version. This is
Fable 5.1. I think that right away this
is a little bit more of an intimidating
interface. It's very, very wordy, but we
can see all of these tests. We can see
our different automations here on the
left as well. We can add a new one. So
if we wanted to put the name, a
description, and then actually, you
know, say how how do you actually
trigger this automation? Is it Python or
do you hit an API? And then from there,
let's just put in some information. You
would actually put in the URL or you
would put in the Python script. You
would put in the test cases and then you
would write, you know, how to grade it.
So that is going to be very valuable.
And it also has all of this stored on
the back end because it has to store all
of these actual um runs and it has to
store the code and it has to you know
show the improvements and things like
that. So here we can see this support
ticket one um I think they ran two
tests. You can see that there's also
like a visual breakdown of what this
actually does. So this is a very
deterministic script. We can see the
code, we can see the setup, we can see
the test cases. So this is essentially
our golden data set. There's only 12
examples. You probably need more than
that. But this was all generated to
actually test the system, right? And if
I actually go in here and hit run, what
does this do? You put the name, you put
what changed, you put any tags, and you
compare it with a different version if
you want. And then I just go ahead and
start the test. And so this came back.
You can see, I mean, there were no
changes. So we still got two out of the
10, or sorry, two out of the 12 didn't
hit, right? It also went super super
fast because I, like I said, this is
super simple. But then you can generate
a report. So I come in here, you can see
all of the different tests that we've
ran. And it would show us like what's
still broken. It would show us the
improvements we make. So this is
something that, you know, I actually do
want to keep building out. So we can do
this for, you know, our our students and
basically give them a better way to
evaluate their agents and things like
that when they're building them out
because eval obviously we all know are
super super important and it's also good
to be able to see them visually. So this
was Fable 5.1's version. Let's look at
Astra's version. So I do like the
interface of this one more as from a
design perspective. I think that this
one feels I don't know it just feels a
little bit more premium. It's also less
wordy so it's less intimidating right
away. I think we have a test library so
we can see all of these different
versions. We have run history. We also
have reports over here that we can look
at. So, we can see customer support
agent. Um, I like how this report is
structured. Let's see if we look at this
next one. We can see how it changes over
time. This one feels more branded. Like,
this feels like something I'd rather get
in front of some eyes and get some
feedback on compared to Oops, I just
closed out of the other one. Compared to
this version, this one just feels way
more like a PC compared to this. I feel
like is, you know, something we can
almost get out there and start testing
against. So, if I come into an
automation real quick, let's say we go
to the support ticket router and I want
to go ahead and see it visually. I like
that a lot. We can see all the previous
runs. And I can go ahead and run this
eval again. And we can see it running a
bit better. We're seeing it actually go
through the test cases. I like this
experience way, way more. And look at
this. Astra came back and cost half the
price of what Fable spent in order to do
this. It did take a little longer, 2
hours 25 minutes compared to an hour and
20 minutes, but it's just so much better
for less cost. So in this case, I'm
giving this to Astra once again. So
Astra is now up, I believe, seven to two
on Fable. All right, moving on to number
10. We now have this Herk brain visual.
So this is a local host where I can see
basically my brain. We see different
clusters over here. Um, this seems more
like YouTube videos. This seems like
things that are actually going on in the
business. Oh, wait. We can see down here
cloud memory, video knowledge, and we
can remove things or put them back in.
Business wiki, skills and agents,
projects, and this is dynamic. It's
really cool because we can see only what
needs attention. We can see show all
labels. We can see 612 notes, 2500
connections. We can analyze things. We
can talk to it. We can search for
things. Let's see if I search for um
personal OS, personal assistant, open
claw. We can open up the specific
things. And that is a pretty cool
visual. So, we can actually start to see
in here inside of the brain. And as we
click on different things, we see all of
the connections that are linking into
it. So, all the relationships. So, that
is a pretty cool experience. It does
feel pretty smooth and I can control
this. Uh, not too well. Like I feel like
I have to click on something to make
that the center, but I I think that
that's pretty cool. So, that was Fable
5.1's version. Let me now open up
Astra's version. Okay, so this one's a
little bit different. Um, I can still
click on all of these things. These
nodes are smaller. I don't like how that
feels. I don't like this interface
at all, like nearly as much. I have the
same sort of vibe. I can click on
business strategy or AI and ideas,
videos and content. Um, people,
projects, book and writing, all
knowledge. Um, this interface is more
overwhelming for sure. Like I I
definitely like this one more. I wanted
just something simple where I can see
the brain a bit more visually. And I was
honestly expecting Astra to come in here
and kick Fable's butt here, but I think
that I like Fables more. And now let's
look at the cost. Astra took 40 minutes.
Fable took 24. Astra and Fable basically
cost the same. Fable was a little bit
cheaper, but I am going to give this one
to Fable. I think that Fable gave me
more of what I was looking for. You
know, once again, kind of a subjective
grading criteria, but I think Fable won
here. So, what does that put us at now?
We're at 7 to three Astra to Fable. And
we have five more use cases left. So,
Fable could still take the lead. All
right, guys. So, this one is an HTML
explainer doc. What I did is I gave it
my YouTube video, the 25 Grockbot
concepts explained, and I told it to
explain it to me simply, simply simply
and visually, and I told it to take
screenshots. I said basically give me a
doc that I can read through and it feels
like I actually watched the entire
tutorial. So we have all these different
parts. We can see the screenshot to
start. This one obviously is is kind of
wordy up front but that's okay. We see
how the team fits together. So me, these
executives, these operators, we can see
all these different plugins and
computers and skills. So that's a good
little explanation at first. Now we move
into the concept. So we're taking
screenshots and it is being analyzed.
This is Fable 5.1 by the way. We can see
the executive bots. We can see the name
and job label. These so far are coming
through well as far as these screenshots
being cropped and annotated which is
really nice. It's taking a lot of
different screenshots. We have the
buttons here. We have all this. I think
that this is coming out pretty well and
it's showing us what we need to see from
the actual video. Now, I do think this
is pretty wordy. Um I think that but it
is getting very specific. Like I do
think I could give this doc to some
people and they would be able to feel
like they actually watched this video.
It's it's cropping things. It's zooming
in. It's annotating. I think that this
is doing a really good job. It's even
showing all of this. Yeah, I mean, this
is doing a really good job here. So,
let's go over to Astro's output. This
one already, it looks a bit better as
far as the HTML. And now, let's see if
the screenshots are good as well. So, we
have one here. It's pointing at a bot.
It is pointing at the description, the
executives, it's pointing at these
different buttons. I will say Fables was
more detailed for sure. Like, this one
was designed better, but Fable's
screenshots were better. like Fable took
more screenshots and made more
annotations. And so far, I think that
that was a better learning experience,
even though this one, like I said, looks
a little bit more I don't know, it it
feels prettier or better. But if you
were really thinking about could you
hand this doc to a complete beginner and
have them actually go through and feel
like they're learning, I think that
Fable's going to take this one. But
let's look at the cost. Like I still am
going to give the output to Fable, but
when we look at the cost, Astra was much
cheaper here. So the question is like,
you know, if you used Astra and had it
spend another, you know, 20 bucks or so,
would it be better than Fable's output
right here? And I would argue that yes,
it would be better. So it was way more
efficient here, but it's, you know, its
V1 wasn't as good as Fable's V1 in my
opinion. So Fable's going to take this
one. So now we are at 7 to4 Fable or 7
to four Astra to Fable. Okay, so moving
on to number 12. We have this sort of
like painting example in Canva, which is
a bit silly, but it does highlight the
browser use and the vision really well
because GBT6 Astra had to look at this
picture, open up Canva, understand how
to navigate with the different tools and
things and build this out, which it did.
And I think that this does look pretty
good, especially when we go over to
Fable real quick and I open up Fable's
output. If I go to the painting and we
open up the browser here, this is
literally what it gave me. And this was
the reference image. I mean, this is
just this is laughable. This is
laughable. I I was expecting Fable 5.1
to do something much better, but it like
I don't know what exactly it tried to
do, but this is obviously just very bad.
So, no question Astro wins this one. And
Astra was also cheaper. So, it's pretty
ridiculous here how much Fable spent and
how long it worked just to give me that
crazy output. So, Astra wins. Okay, so
moving on to the next example, number
13. What I did is I gave Fable and Astra
this doc which said, "Hey, these are
this is a new course. I want you to put
it into the free community as a draft
and I want you to use browser use in
order to do this." So they basically
opened up school. They went to the
classroom and they put in these draft
courses, Astra AIOS and Fable AIOS and
they put in their different courses. So
they were basically instructed to have
the description, the key points, the key
quotes, and any resources. And they had
to put the video in here. And so this is
Astra's output. I told them to do just
the first five. And this looks really
good. It had to navigate the interface.
It had to basically come in here, make a
new page. It had to put in the video. It
had to put in the text. And it did it
really well and saved everything here as
a draft. Now, if we go to Fable's
output, there are no videos here. This
one arguably might have been structured
better as far as like this looks cool
and these are numbered, whereas the
other one with Astra, it wasn't like
numbered as well. Like it just it's
longer. But the big big issue here is
that Fable ran into an issue and for
some reason couldn't upload the video.
There was something issue with having it
download locally and whatnot. you know,
I gave them everything it needed. I gave
them the videos. I gave it the links.
This is something that Asha did way
better. And I will say I've done this
multiple times in my school. And I've
used 5.6 soul with browser use. And just
in general, codecs and the GBT models
are significantly better with browser
use. So, this one I'm going to give to
Astra. And honestly, the cost and the
time wasn't too different here, you
know. Um, very similar and very similar.
Astra was a little bit cheaper and
Astra's results were much much better.
So, this one's going to go to Astra as
well. So we are now at the place where
the score is Astro has nine and Fable
has four. So Fable can no longer catch
up. But let's look at the last two
outputs as well. Okay. So for number 14,
we did a website and basically what I
wanted to happen is I gave it this URL
and I said, "Hey, I want you to
basically help me clone this website. I
like the structure. I like the feel and
I want you to make this for Perk Form,
which is the fake, you know, um, can
company." So this is a really cool
scroll dynamic. I know you guys, some of
you guys hate this sort of site. That's
not the point. The point is, could Astra
and Fable analyze this site and make one
that has the same feel and the same vibe
for Pork Farm? So, here is Fable 5.1's
version. It loads up. We have this, you
know, 3D dynamic element, coffee
reformed. We have like some, you know,
DNA looking stuff here. We keep
scrolling down. We've got these coffee
beans falling. We've got the can come
back. We've got all this going on. I
would say that it's doing a decent job
here. It's even got the huge like zoom
out. It's doing a decent job of making
this feel like the other site. You know,
obviously there are some issues here,
but I think it's doing a decent job.
Like for a oneshot prompt, although
sometimes I get into these issues with
the scroll. I mean, that's a bit of a
bug, right? That's when you hit the
bottom of the site, something weird goes
on there. So, there's obviously some
bugs, but it's not terrible for a
oneshot. And now, let's take a look at
Astra's version. We have the big can
here, which is a little bit dynamic.
There's something going on with this
text, right? Like the coffee is out of
bounds for some reason. Keep scrolling
down. I do like this animation. I mean,
that's pretty cool. It's a It's a coffee
bean. There's definitely layers in the
back. And by the way, this one I didn't
tell it to use any skills. I just said,
"Hey, I want the same vibe. I want you
to analyze the, you know, the original
site, this one right here, and make me
one like this." Right? So, anyways,
we're coming through the little sort of
like DNA thing. Coffee and protein
together, two drinks in one can. I like
that animation. This one overall does
feel smoother than Fables. I do think
that as far as a first pass, I like the
way this one feels. we get stuck at the
bottom and we'd have to scroll all the
way back up to the top. Now, I do think
that Fable did a better job as of
actually just recreating what we saw in
the original site, which was the prompt.
Now, I do get stuck. There's a little
bit of a there's bugs like this. Like, I
get stuck. But, as far as recreating
this, Fables felt more similar to this,
I think. So, we will give this one to
Fable. Um, it kind of needs it as well.
But, I still think in general, when it
comes to design, you guys have probably
seen throughout this video and you've
seen my other videos. In general, I do
think I like Astram more for design, but
that was like, "Hey, show me what you
can do. Take this URL. Build me
something crazy in one shot." It was
kind of a weird prompt, right? But in
this case, I still think that Fable won.
But here's a look at the cost and the
time for this example. All right. And
this is the last one. Number 15. We have
YouTube 12-month review and strategy.
So, it basically had to look through the
past year of my YouTube stuff and give
me some stats. So, this is interesting.
I mean, these are big docs. The one on
the left is Fable. It's 25 pages. The
one on the right is Astra. It's 15
pages. So let's just slowly scroll
through and see what's happening here. I
like how Astra right away has you know
this chart on new viewers and regular
viewers whereas over here we have you
know the year and numbers we have a
monthly review. We have total views
across the past um ooh interesting. So
actually what they show me first on the
left side is from January to now whereas
over here I'm getting sort of like the
actual past 12 months. So those stats
are going to be a little bit different.
It's showing me content type. It's
showing me the monthly scorecard. It's
showing what my best content actually
does. It's showing me some packaging
stuff. It's showing me what to worry
about. So, it says news brings the views
but does not bring the subscribers. It's
saying um the news packaging is drifting
towards hype. The audience is saying so.
It's saying agency mechanics content has
stopped working on YouTube. That
definitely feels to be a bit true for
this audience. Now, it's deep diving
into some packaging. So, it's analyzing
my my titles over here. Whereas over
here, when we have the packaging, um
what I would keep and improve, the
evidence, retention, first 30 seconds,
who you are reaching and how. So, it's
looking at the age, it's looking at the
gender, it's looking at the geography,
it analyzes what the comments are asking
me to do. So, then at the end, they kind
of like put all this stuff together and
they give me the next 90 days and they
give me some things to look at. Overall,
they're very similar. I do like the way
that this was packaged more by Astra. It
just feels a little bit easier to read
and it also feels more visual. So, I'm
going to give this one to Astra as well.
And you can see here though, Astra did
spend more and take longer. So, 42
minutes compared to 17 and 27 bucksish
compared to N bucks. So, Astra wins, but
it was longer or slower and more
expensive here. But anyways, guys, that
was 15. That was 15 different use cases
here that we scored and looked at the
cost and time. Astra won 10 of them and
Fable won five of them. But let's take a
look at the total numbers here. I had
both Astra and Fable give me these stats
to make sure they were consistent. And
you can see the numbers are exactly the
same. Fable was 9 hours 35 minutes and
45 seconds of total run time here
costing us 513 bucks.36
and Astra was 11 hours 19 minutes 24
seconds and cost us 326 bucks.98. So in
total Astra was $186
cheaper but took an hour and 43 minutes
longer to run across these 15 different
use cases. Now I will say this was 15
use cases. In general, my experience has
been that Astra feels quicker and feels
more efficient and also it doesn't give
us that 5 hour window in Codeex and it
doesn't give us that fable limit. You
know, we can just use Astra the whole
week. So, I do like that we also get
more inference with Astra in general
because of the codec subscription. So,
right now I'm heavily leaning towards
Astra for my my day-to-day my use cases.
But the other thing I want you guys to
keep in mind is that GBT 5.6 Soul is so
so good still. It's so capable and for
the majority of my knowledge work, I
could use that just fine. And that even
honestly might be overkill for the
majority of stuff that I'm doing. So
it's not like you need to use Astra only
for all your use cases. And it's not
like you need to go grab Fable 5.1 for
all your use cases. I'm still a very
firm believer in they both have
different strengths and weaknesses. They
both have value. And that's why I love
doing things like this to find out what
are the different use cases and how do
they, you know, behave in different
scenarios. And so yes, I am going to be
using codeex more right now because
that's where it currently is. But this
stuff shifts so fast and I will always
keep both subscriptions or multiple of
both subscriptions so I can keep testing
them out as things change, as my use
cases change. Who knows what might
happen. But anyways, that is going to do
it for this one. I hope you guys enjoyed
this breakdown. I hope that it was
insightful or you learned something new.
And if you did, please give it a like.
It helps me out a ton. And as always, I
appreciate you guys making it to the end
of the video. And I'll see you guys all
in the next one. Thanks everyone.